Guide to the New York Feminist Art Institute Archived Websites MSS.615
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York Feminist Art Institute Archived Websites
January 2010-January 2022
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York Feminist Art Institute/Women's Center for Learning
MSS.615
11 websites in 11 archived websites.
The New York Feminist Art Institute (NYFAI) was founded 1979 by to create an environment for the training of women in the arts. NYFAI was active as a school from 1979-1990, and the Ceres Gallery exhibited their work. In 1993, the organization ceased operations, but a website was developed documenting the NYFAI oral history project, activities of former members of NYFAI, and events related to feminism and art in New York City.
Related Materials
Rutgers University holds the Records of the New York Feminist Art Institute (MC 892).
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Custodial History
http://nyfai.org/ was initially selected by Tamiment curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2010 as part of the Feminism and Women's Movements Web Archive. In November 2015, the website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2015 http://nyfai.org/ was transferred to Fales Library and http://www.katemillett.com/, https://www.cla.purdue.edu/waaw/corinne/Raven.htm, http://www.cheimread.com/artists/louise-fishman, http://www.joanroth.com/, http://www.phyllisrosser.com/, https://www.brooklynmuseum.org/eascfa/feminist_art_base/, http://www.faithringgold.com/, http://www.darlabjork.com/, http://www.nancyazara.com/, and http://www.judychicago.com/ were added.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Appraisal
Artists websites were set up to capture the homepages of their websites only.
Arrangement
Arranged by date added to Archive-It.
Historical Note
The New York Feminist Art Institute (NYFAI) was founded 1979 by Miriam Schapiro, Carol Stonghilos, Nancy Azara, Irene Peslikis, Lucille Lessane, and Selena Whitefeather to create an environment for the training of women in the arts. NYFAI was active as a school from 1979-1990, and the Ceres Gallery exhibited their work. In 1993, the organization ceased operations. In the 2000s, founders, faculty, students and others major participants in NYFAI were interviewed as part of an oral history project. In addition, a travelling exhibit, Visual Diaries, was curated based on Nancy Azara's Consciousness Raising Workshop in circa 2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the website for the New York Feminist Art Institute from 2010-2017, which documents the legacy of the organization. The website consists of a brief history of the organization, articles written about and for NYFAI, and the homepages of board members and instructors involved with NYFAI. The website also consists of digitized images, art, and catalogs created by members and the organization from 1979-1990. The website also documents the NYFAI oral history project, activities of former members of NYFAI, and events related to feminism and art in New York City.
Feminism and art -- New York (State) -- New York.; Feminism in art; Art -- Political aspects -- New York (State) -- New York; Millett, Kate; Chicago, Judy, 1939-; Azara, Nancy J., 1939-; Bjork, Darla; Ringgold, Faith; Rosser, Phyllis; Fishman, Louise, 1939-2021; Roth, Joan; Raven, Arlene; Brooklyn Museum
- New York Feminist Art Institute, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Contents
  The New York Feminist Art Institute (NYFAI) was founded 1979 by to create an environment for the training of women in the arts. NYFAI was active as a school from 1979-1990, and the Ceres Gallery exhibited their work. In 1993, the organization ceased operations, but a website was developed documenting the NYFAI oral history project, activities of former members of NYFAI, and events related to feminism and art in New York City.
- Judy Chicago, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Nancy Azara, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Darla Bjork, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Faith Ringgold, January 2010-January 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Feminist Art Base, May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Phyllis Rosser, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Joan Roth, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Louise Fishman, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Arlene Raven, January 2010-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
- Kate Millet, January 2010-July 2011 (Box Electronic Records)